vcs.co.za 2018-04-05

# Privacy Policy | Secure Online Payments | Payment Gateway

**1.APPLICABILITY**

1.1 This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which VCS collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (“ **User/s** “) of the [vcs.co.za](http://www.vcs.co.za/) Website (“ **Website** “). This Privacy Policy applies to the Website and all services marketed and supplied by VCS (“ **VCS** ”/” **we** ”/” **us** ”/” **our** ”).

**2.  PERSONAL IDENTIFICATION INFORMATION**

2.1 VCS may collect personal identification information from Users, with their consent, in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Website, fill out a form or an order, participate in the VCS Support Blog (available to registered VCS merchants) and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Website.

2.2 Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, surname, email address, physical address and/or phone number in order for you to contact us or place an order. Users may, however, visit our Website anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Website related activities.

**3\. NON-PERSONAL IDENTIFICATION INFORMATION**

3.1 We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Website. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users’ means of connection to our Website, such as the operating system and the Internet service provider’s utilized and other similar information.

**  4\. WEB BROWSER COOKIES**

4.1 Our Website may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. A User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. A User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Website may not function properly.

  **5\. HOW WE USE COLLECTED INFORMATION**

 5.1 VCS collects and uses Users’ personal information for the following purposes –

5.1.1 To perform in terms of the agreements it has with VCS merchants.

5.1.2 To improve customer service. Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.

5.1.3 To respond to requests from VCS merchants posted on the VCS Support Blog.

5.1.4 To analyse content performance on the VCS Support Blog.

5.1.5 Should you agree thereto, to send periodic emails regarding new or current products. The email address Users provide will be used to respond to their inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

**6\. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**

6.1 We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Website.

6.2 We will not use your personal information for any purpose (other than as stated above) without your express consent. We will not use or disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent, unless the use or disclosure is –

6.2.1 required to carry out the performance of the agreement between VCS and the VCS merchant;

6.2.2required in order to comply with applicable law, order of court or legal process; and/or

6.2.3 disclosure is necessary to protect and defend the legitimate interests of VCS.

 6.3 We undertake to –

6.31 treat your personal information as strictly confidential;

6.3.2 take appropriate security measures to ensure that your personal information is kept secure and is protected against unauthorised or unlawful processing, alteration, disclosure or access, accidental loss, destruction or damage;

 6.3.3 promptly notify you if we become aware of any unauthorised use, disclosure or processing of your personal information;

6.3.4 provide you with reasonable evidence of our compliance with our obligations under this policy on reasonable notice and request; and

6.3.5 upon your request, promptly return or destroy any and all of your personal information in our possession or control.

6.4 We will not retain your personal information longer than the period for which it was originally needed, unless we are required by law to do so, or you consent to us retaining such information for a longer period.

6.5 If you disclose your personal information to a third party via a website linked to the Website or anyone other than VCS, VCS shall not be liable for any loss or damage, howsoever arising, suffered by you as a result of the disclosure of such information to the third party. Please refer to the privacy policy of that third party.

**7\. SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

7.1 We do not sell, trade, or rent Users’ personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.

**8\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

8.1 VCS has the discretion to update this Privacy Policy at any time. When we do, we will, revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect.

8.2 By using this Website, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use this Website. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

**9\. CONTACTING US**

9.1 If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us via our Contact Details page on the Website.

_Date last updated 10 June 2016._
